Yeah, and deserves on Linux too a lot of people don't realize how much Microsoft
really does use Linux a lot now and
Yeah, it's not going anywhere. I'm hell Microsoft
I think pays a couple million a year to be on the Linux Foundation as like a gold platinum partner or whatever it's called
so
They they don't want Linux to disappear Microsoft's not anti Linux if anything
They're just trying to use it because a lot of free and open-source software projects do get used
Buy it. So yeah in free BSD
I'm actually making a video about like Sony PlayStation how it uses free BSD and just abuses the hell out of it
Well, I wouldn't say abuse maybe I may yeah
Because they don't really don't contribute that much for as much as they've profited off of free BSD. I
Have not seen very many commits from them. I have not seen I think most of the bug requests are more out of
Like bug reports are more out of hey, this isn't working for us kind of thing. Hey BSD team
Can you do it? I think the benefit to BSD and having like Sony use them is
They get a lot more eyeballs on them as a project. So a little bit there
But the main issue I have with BSD compared to Linux is Linux runs a
GPL license which means you have to keep it open source if you do make a project based on it
You have to have the code somewhere and it has to be public so people could look at it
We're BSD is an MIT license meaning you can take all their code and then write a whole bunch of proprietary
closed stuff and then lock it away somewhere and they never have to show the world that again much like how Sony PlayStation does
So it's kind of an interesting dynamic between
BSD and PlayStation which I'm gonna explore a little bit more in an upcoming video. Yeah, Microsoft's a platinum member. That's right
BSD has a license. I thought free BSD just uses MIT license, which is pretty darn open
At least last time I checked
And they it's not like Sony doesn't contribute back at all
It's just they don't contribute out very much at all and the last time I'm thinking back to like Sony PlayStation 3's the fat design
When it originally released it had a Linux
You could actually install Linux on it and I actually did that back in I think it was the late 2000s and
It was cool, but a lot of times people were using it for home brewing
I know I was and it was make it made the Sony PlayStation a lot more hackable and that's why I think they removed
it I think I was they even sent me like a class action lawsuit
participation and stuff and
Yeah, that was that was interesting to say the least I
Think I got like four dollars from it or three dollars
Anytime there's class action lawsuit involved the only people that win is the lawyers